Guide to the David Henry Hwang Papers, ca. 1985-1992
Department of Special Collections
David Henry Hwang Papers,
ca. 1985-1992
Special Collections M636
Hwang, David Henry, 1957-
17.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of David H. Hwang, 1991 and 1992.
BIOGRAPHY
David Henry Hwang is an award-winning playwright whose work often deals with the manipulation or breakdown of stereotypes--particularly those concerning Asian-Americans--while exploring the frontiers of experimental drama. Hwang, a creative writing major who studied with Stanford professor John L'Heureux, graduated from the university in 1979. He credits L'Heureux and playwright Sam Shepard as early influences.
M. Butterfly, the best known of Hwang's plays, won Broadway's Tony Award in 1988. In the years following M. Butterfly's success Hwang has moved toward filmwriting, exploring the Asian-American experience in films such as Golden Gate, the collection's most recent piece, which was filmed on location in San Francisco in 1992.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Includes original manuscripts, corrected typescripts, etc. for both major and minor works including M. BUTTERFLY, BONDAGE, and 1000 AIRPLANES ON THE ROOF.
CONTAINER LIST
- Essays (Box 1a, Folder 1)
- "Sunday Sermon"/"Hypocrites No More" (Box 1a, Folder 2)
- "Free at Last" (Box 1a, Folder 3)
- "M. Butterfly" (Box 1a, Folder 4-5)
- "Jan Ken Po" (Box 1a, Folder 6)
- "Devil May Care" (Box 1a, Folder 7)
- "Rich Relations" (Box 1a, Folder 8-11)
- "1000 Airplanes on the Roof" (Box 1b (o.s))
- "Rich Relations" (originals) (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
- "Over the Edge" (originals) (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
- "CL" (originals) (Box 2, Folder 9-12)
- "MF" (originals) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- "7 Years in Tibet" (originals) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- unknown originals (Box 2, Folder 15-17)
- correspondence: originals (Box 3, Folder 1)
- correspondence: originals: Merrill and Attorneys (Box 3, Folder 2)
- National Endowment for the Arts: applications (Box 3, Folder 3)
- newspaper/magazine clippings (Box 3, Folder 4)
- synopsis (Box 3, Folder 5)
- "American Dreams" (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "New World" (Box 3, Folder 7)
- "San Francisco" (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Government Councils: Theatre Communications Group & California Arts (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Writers Agency (Box 3, Folder 10)
- "Rich Relations": Agreements (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Contracts: "Good Fortune" (Box 3, Folder 12)
- "Devil May Care" (Box 3, Folder 13)
- "M. Butterfly" (Box 3, Folder 14)
- "M. Butterfly" (Box 4, Folder 1)
- "Good Fortune" (Box 4, Folder 2)
- "Seven Years in Tibet" (Box 4, Folder 3)
- "Year Without Michael" (Box 4, Folder 4)
- "M. Butterfly" (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
- "M. Butterfly": Corrections (Box 4, Folder 7)
- "M. Butterfly": Cuts (Box 4, Folder 8)
- "M. Butterfly": Original Housing (Box 4, Folder 9)
- "M. Butterfly" Contract (Box 5, Folder 1)
- "FOB": Contracts (Box 5, Folder 2)
- "FOB": Interview (Box 5, Folder 3)
- "FOB": Original and Draft (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Stage design: Plenter and Horivichi (Box 5, Folder 5)
- "The Dance of the Railroad": originals and copy prints (Box 5, Folder 6-11)
- "The Dance of the Railroad": Cricket Theatre (Box 5, Folder 12)
- "The Dance of the Railroad": Production Material (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Unknown original (yellow pad) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- "Family Devotion" (Box 5, Folder 15)
- "Family Devotion" (Box 5, Folder 16)
- "Family Devotion": Original Housing (Box 5, Folder 17)
- "Rich Relations" (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Correspondence; Madame Butterfly libretto (Puccini) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Contracts: "Dr. Haing Ngor Project" (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Approved Production Contract for Plays (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Articles: "Why Not Sort of Pregnant?" (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Television Writing Contract: "Dr. Haing Ngor MFT" (Box 6, Folder 6)
- "Good Intentions" (Box 6, Folder 7)
- "Free at Last" (Box 6, Folder 8)
- "Destiny: The Story of Dr. Haing S. Ngor" (Box 6, Folder 9)
- "Destiny: The Story of Dr. Haing S. Ngor": Original Housing (Box 6, Folder 10)
- "Cheap Tales" (Box 6, Folder 11)
- "Unnatural Acts": The Cricket Theatre (Box 6, Folder 12)
- "Family Devotions" (originals & copy prints) (Box 7, Folder 1-12)
- "Family Devotions": contracts (Box 7, Folder 13)
- "The House of Sleeping Beauties": (originals & copy prints) (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
- "Sound and Beauty," "The House of Sleeping Beauties": Production Material (Box 8, Folder 6)
- "New Worlds"/ "Letters from the East" (included) (Box 8, Folder 7)
- "New Worlds" (Box 8, Folder 8)
- "Leading the Blind" (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Agreement: Kletter & Hwang (Box 8, Folder 10)
- "Unnatural Acts": Stage designs, clippings, brochures (Box 9, Folder 1)
- "Unnatural Acts" (Box 9, Folder 2)
- "Unnatural Acts": Original Housing (Box 9, Folder 3)
- American Playhouse; T.V. Agreements (Box 9, Folder 4)
- "Jan Ken Po" (Box 9, Folder 5)
- "Good Intentions" (Box 9, Folder 6)
- "Igo Ono": Business Material (Box 9, Folder 7)
- "Sound of a Voice" (Box 9, Folder 8)
- "Igo Ono" (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
- "Igo Ono": Preliminary Material (Box 10, Folder 1)
- "Igo Ono" (Box 10, Folder 2-10)
- "As the Crow Flies" (Box 10, Folder 11)
- ("Sunset in Noriega"?): 2 originals (Box 10, Folder 12-13)
- "A Chinaman's Chance" (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Newspaper/ Magazine Articles (Box 11, Folder 1-11)
- "Yellow Fever": A play by Rich Shiomi (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Magazines and Brochures (Box 12)
- Photographs (Box 13)
- Original Newspapers (Box 14)
- Posters (Box 15)
- "2-2 Utterly Utterly": screenplay (Box 16, Folder 1)
- "2-2 Utterly Utterly": movie material (Box 16, Folder 2)
- "2-2 Utterly Utterly": Treatment (McLaren) (Box 16, Folder 3)
- "2-2 Utterly Utterly": Originals (yellow pads) (Box 16, Folder 4-11)
- "The Voyage" (Box 16, Folder 12)
- "The Voyage": libretto (Box 16, Folder 13)
- "The Visitors": First Draft (Box 16, Folder 14)
- "1000 Airplanes on the Roof" (Box 17, Folder 1)
- "1000 Airplanes on the Roof"Production Schedule (Box 17, Folder 2)
- "1000 Airplanes on the Roof"Itineraries (Box 17, Folder 3)
- "1000 Airplanes on the Roof"Preliminary storyboards (Box 17, Folder 4)
- "Bondage": First Draft (Box 17, Folder 5)
- "Bondage": Second Draft (Box 17, Folder 6)
- "Bondage": Louisville Drafts (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Humana Festival materials (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Humana Festival schedules (Box 17, Folder 9)
- "M. Butterfly": Contracts, script updates (Box 17, Folder 10)
- "M. Butterfly": Screenplay, Second Draft (Box 18, Folder 1)
- "Bondage": Notes (Box 18, Folder 2)
- "M. Butterfly": First Draft (Box 18, Folder 3)
- "M. Butterfly": copy (Box 18, Folder 4)
- "M. Butterfly": Screenplay, First Draft (Box 18, Folder 5)
- "M. Butterfly": Screenplay, Second Draft (Box 18, Folder 6)
- "M. Butterfly": Filmscript Originals (yellow pads) (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
- "M. Butterfly": Treatment and First Draft (Box 19, Folder 4)
- "M. Butterfly": Notes and Draft (Box 19, Folder 5)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Notes and Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 6)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Screenplay, Rough Draft (Box 20, Folder 1)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Second Draft (Box 20, Folder 2)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Draft (Apr. 22, 1990) (Box 20, Folder 3)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Development Materials (Box 20, Folder 4)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Draft (Dec. 27, 1989) (Box 20, Folder 5)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Draft (May 6, 1990) (Box 20, Folder 6)
- "Seven Years in Tibet": Draft (computer printout) (Box 21, Folder 1)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Rough Draft (Aug. 17, 1987) (Box 21, Folder 2)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Second Draft (Dec. 20, 1988) (Box 21, Folder 3)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Draft fragment (Box 21, Folder 4)
- "Seven years in Tibet": First Draft and Correspondence (Box 21, Folder 5)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Original Rewrites (yellow pads) (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
- "Seven years in Tibet": Rewrites (yellow pads) (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
- "A Chinaman's Chance": Draft & Miscellaneous Notes (Box 23, Folder 1)
- "Spring Wind": Drafts (Box 23, Folder 2)
- "My American Son": Teleplay, Second Draft (Box 23, Folder 3)
- "Golden Gate": First and Third Drafts (Box 23, Folder 4)
- "Golden Gate": Third Draft (Box 23, Folder 5)
- "Red Angel": Second Draft (Box 23, Folder 6)
- "Golden Gate": Fourth Draft (Box 24, Folder 1)
- "Playhouse": Originals (yellow pads) (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
- "Playhouse": Original Rewrites (yellow pads) (Box 24, Folder 4-5)